const questions = [
  {
    question: "What is the standard tuning for a six-string guitar from low to high?",
    options: ["a) E A D G B E", "b) A D G B E A", "c) D G C E A D", "d) G C E A D G"],
    correctAnswer: "a) E A D G B E",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the term for the technique of using a pick to strike the strings in a downward motion followed by an upward motion?",
    options: ["a) Hammer-on", "b) Pull-off", "c) Alternate picking", "d) Slide"],
    correctAnswer: "c) Alternate picking",
  },
  {
    question: "Which part of the guitar is responsible for adjusting the pitch of the strings?",
    options: ["a) Fretboard", "b) Headstock", "c) Bridge", "d) Neck"],
    correctAnswer: "b) Headstock",
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of guitar is known for its hollow body and is often used in jazz music?",
    options: ["a) Acoustic guitar", "b) Classical guitar", "c) Electric guitar", "d) Archtop guitar"],
    correctAnswer: "d) Archtop guitar",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of a capo?",
    options: ["a) Adjusting the guitar's volume", "b) Changing the guitar's tuning", "c) Muting the strings", "d) Shortening the playable length of the strings"],
    correctAnswer: "d) Shortening the playable length of the strings",
  },{
    question: "What is the name of the small piece of plastic used to fret a note on the guitar?",
    options: ["a) Slide","b) Pick","c) Capo","d) Finger"],
    correctAnswer: "d) Finger",
  },

  {
    question: "Which of the following is not a type of electric guitar pickup?",
    options: ["a) Single-coil","b) Humbucker"," c) Piezo", "d) Dipole],"],
    correctAnswer:"d) Dipole"
  },
  {
    question: "What does the term 'bend' refer to in guitar playing?",
    options: ["a) Striking the strings with the back of the fingernails","b) Changing the pitch of a note by pushing the string upwards","c) Playing two notes simultaneously", "d) Muting the strings with the palm of the hand"],
    correctAnswer:"b) Changing the pitch of a note by pushing the string upwards"
  },
  {
    question: "Which famous guitarist is known for his use of the 'whammy bar' in rock music?",
    options: ["a) Eric Clapton", "b) Jimi Hendrix", "c) Eddie Van Halen","d) Jimmy Page"],
    correctAnswer:"c) Eddie Van Halen"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the soundhole in an acoustic guitar?",
    options: ["a) Enhancing the guitar's aesthetics", "b) Allowing air to move in and out, affecting the sound","c) Providing a place to hang the guitar","d) Acting as a storage compartment" ],
    correctAnswer:"b) Allowing air to move in and out, affecting the sound"
  }
  // Add more questions as needed
];

export default questions;